

### Kobus van Schoor

Computer Engineering Student

#### **PROFILE**

Address Pretoria, South Africa

Website

https://kobusvs.co.za

**Email Address** v.schoor.kobus@gmail.com

Github

kobus-v-schoor

LinkedIn

kobus-van-schoor

#### **SKILLS**

#### Linux

3+ years of experience with Linux systems administration and security in a production environment (Debianbased distributions)

Well-versed in using C++ as an OOP-language with templating and automated testing. Used for general-purpose development as well as AI.

#### Bash

Experienced in using Bash to write generalpurpose scripts for systems administration.

### **Ansible**

Experience in using Ansible to automate DevOps in both a production environment as well as for personal use

#### **Embedded** Development

Have developed for STM, PIC and Arduino platforms. Some experience with Verilog and VHDL for FPGA development.

### **Pvthon**

Experienced using Python for AI, web development, and general-purpose programming in automated test and deployment environments

### Keras, Tensorflow and Sci-kit Learn

Experience with learning frameworks such as Tensorflow, Keras and scikit-learn in a personal capacity

#### Django

Developed multiple websites in Django including a system to deploy jobs to a HPC

## 3D Printing and

Experienced in using FreeCAD to do part design for 3D printing. Successfully designed and printed complex multi-part systems.

# **Analog Circuit**

Design

Some experience in designing analog circuitry (mostly for University)

### **AWARDS**

#### **Cloudflight Coding Contest Top-**35 Worldwide Cloudflight

October

September

Placed 32nd internationally in the 34th Cloudflight Coding Contest, a coding competition where you have 4 hours to solve problems of varying difficulty.

#### **Entelect Challenge 2020 Finalist**

Entelect Software

Finalist in the Entelect Challenge, a programming competition where you design an AI to compete against other players. Placed 4th in the finals.

## **OBIECTIVE**

I am a maker who is passionate about electronics, programming, and building intelligent systems. I want to make an impact by building things that can help other people and I'm always open to learning something new.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Team Lead: Full stack Developer and Linux Systems Administrator

Department of Computer Science, University of Pretoria

(lanuary 2021 - Present)

Along with my previous duties (see below), I acted as team lead for the TechTeam. My responsibilities included the following:

- Identification of new team projects, decisions on project timelines and overseeing their development
- Code review of all newly implemented major projects
- Developing a new user management portal and code auto-marking system (FitchFork) for the Department. Successfully implemented and migrated from legacy systems.
- Handling hardware procurement
- Training of new TechTeam staff

#### Full stack Developer and Linux Systems Administrator Department of Computer Science, University of Pretoria

(January 2018 - December 2020)

While studying at the University of Pretoria I also worked as a full-stack developer and systems administrator for the Department of Computer Science. Working in a small team, we managed and developed the infrastructure that several critical services in the department operated on. My responsibilities included the following:

- Administration of several critical services for the Department of Computer Science including LDAP and Kerberos central authentication, course websites, auto-marker facilities and websites for research groups
- Designed the architecture and set up the MITC high-performance cluster which is used by post-graduate students to perform research on big-data machine learning applications
- Administration of several hundred lab computers running Linux with central LDAP authentication and home folder hosting for use by students
- Maintained the main CS website as well as the auto-marker assignments website

#### EDUCATION

### University of Pretoria

BEng. Computer Engineering

(January 2017 - December 2021)

Currently in my final year of studying Computer Engineering at the University of Pretoria.

### PROJECTS

#### Dotgit

https://github.com/kobus-v-schoor/dotgit

Lead developer and maintainer of dotgit, a comprehensive dotfiles (configuration files) manager which allows you to store and organize your dotfiles on multiple machines. Active user base with a completely automated CI/CD pipeline. First developed in bash and now currently in Python.

### Designed and built a 3D Printer

https://kobusvs.co.za/blog/3d-printer/

Designed, printed and built my own DIY 3D printer which I actively use for DIY projects.

### MITC high-performance cluster

https://kobusvs.co.za/blog/ha-cluster-no-magic/

Designed and set up the MITC high-performance cluster for the Department of Computer Science at the University of Pretoria which is used by post-graduate students to perform research on big-data machine learning applications

#### E-commerce website for baking goods and packaging business https://www.bakersparadise.co.za

Developed an e-commerce website from the ground up in Django for a baking goods and packaging supplier expanding into online sales and deliveries.

### Automated Forex trading software

https://www.mql5.com/en/market/product/15328

Developed proprietary Forex and commodity trading software to automate trading strategies. Currently in active use.

### Cluedo Al

https://github.com/kobus-v-schoor/cluedo-ai

Developed an AI to play the classic board-game Cluedo for a university project. Implemented path-finding, offensive and defensive strategies and also a comprehensive set of rules to quickly deduce the other player's cards

### Homelab

Built a homelab on which I maintain several services for personal use. All the services are managed using industry-standard methods (automated deployment using Ansible, microservices deployed on containers) and follow best-practices. The services include homeautomation, backup solutions and data-science environments which are also used by family and friends.

### Other Projects

https://kobusvs.co.za/tags/projects/

Some of the other projects I've worked on can be found on my personal website.